ATHIF AHAMED

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

athifahamedj@gmail.com +91 7904811526

https://www.linkedin.com/in/athif-ahamed 519ab1183

skype: athifahamedj@outlook.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Creative Full stack Developer offering 1+ year of experience providing high-impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in designing, developing and deploying multiple web-based applications incorporating a range of technologies.

Aspiring to combine broad debugging, performance improvement learning with strong technical skills to excel as a Full stack Developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Javascript, Jquery, Ajax
- React Js & Redux
- PHP, MySQL
- Laravel, Codeigniter
- Wordpress
- Git & GitHub

INTERESTS

- Reading novels
- Writing blogs
- Solving puzzles
- Video Games

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

• Tamil, English

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full stack web developer

One year & Five months hands-on experience

- Developed responsive applications on both front and backend using PHP, JavaScript, Jquery, Ajax, Bootstrap, HTML and CSS with MySQL database.
- Worked on PHP frameworks such as Laravel and Codeigniter with MySQL databases for storing and retrieving datas.
- Worked on a React Js and Redux to improve performance of applications using react hooks and lifecycle methods along with REST apis, Git and GitHub functionalities.
- Developed dynamic websites for Ecommerce, POS on Wordpress sites including payment gateway such as paytm, paypal etc.
- Designed, developed and deployed user friendly Applications with improved web performance and responsiveness.

ANUR CLOUD TECHNOLOGIES

Software Engineer | 20/10/2022 - present

Currently working in applications that supports PHP, Laravel, MySQL with APIs for backend development whereas HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, React js with redux for front end designing.

GBS Systems and Services

PHP developer | 31/03/2021 - 30/09/2021

Worked as a Full stack Web developer in POS App development with various PDFs and API technologies.

Softlogic Academy

Web technologies | 19/01/2019 - 21/04/2019

Certified course and trained on languages such as HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP.

EDUCATION HIGHLIGHTS

Aalim muhammed salegh college of engineering

Electronics and communication | 2015 - 2019

• CGPA - 6.7/10

Sri venkateshwara matric. higher sec school, Chennai.

Higher Secondary | 2015

• 70.50%

Saraswathi vidyalaya matric. higher sec school, Muthupet. $SSLC \mid 2013$

• 94%